KWAN, Kin Chung (KC)

Researcher - CG & HCI

I am a researcher in Computer Graphics (CG) and a Ph.D. in Computer Science from the Chinese University of Hong Kong in 2015. My research experience is in Non-Photorealistic Rendering (NPR), augmented reality as well as Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) for 11+ years. I published multiple technical research papers in top conferences and journals, such as SIGGRAPH (Asia), TVCG, CGF, and CHI. I have experience of lecturing and was a teaching assistant for nine different courses, such as multimedia and game development.

Research Interests

Visual computing, computer graphics, human-computer interaction, non-photorealistic rendering, augmented reality

Education

2015	Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong
2009	B.Sc. in Computer Science The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Academic Experiences

2020 – present	Postdoctoral Research Fellow University of Konstanz, Germany
	First author paper in SIGGRAPH Asia
2018 – 2020	Senior Research Assistant
2017 – 2018	Postdoctoral Research Fellow
2017 2010	City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong
	First author papers in SIGGRAPH, SIGCHI, CGF
	Co-author paper in TVCG
2015 – 2017	Research Fellow
2014 – 2015	Research Assistant
	Caritas Institute of Higher Education, Hong Kong
	 First author papers in SIGGRAPH Asia, TVCG
	Ph.D. Thesis
2013 – 2014	Research Assistant
	The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Teaching Experiences

Teacher, University	<u>of Konstanz, Germany</u>
2021 – 2022	Illustrative Computer Graphics (Bachelor)

Teaching Assistant, University of Konstanz, Germany

2020 - 2022Current Trends in Computer Graphics (Graduate)

<u>i eacnin</u>	<u>g Assistant</u>	, The Chi	<u>nese Universi</u>	ty of Hong	Kong, Hong	<u> Kong</u>

2015 – 2018	Web-Based Graphics and Virtual Reality (<i>Graduate</i>)
2014 – 2017	Mobile Apps Design and Implementation (Graduate)
2013 – 2019	Computer Game Software Production (Graduate)
2013	Multimedia Technology (Graduate)
2011 – 2012	Advanced GPU Programming (Graduate)
2010 – 2011	Introduction to Multimedia Systems (Bachelor)
2010	Principles of Computer Game Software (Bachelor)
2009	Introduction to Computing Using Java (Bachelor)

Teacher, The Hong Kong Jockey Club, Hong Kong CUDA Training (Industry) 2015



Date of Birth 05 Aug 1987

> Gender Male

Nationality Chinese (Hong Kong) British Nationals (Overseas)

Language

Cantonese				
English				
Mandarin				_
Japanese			_	_
German	_	_	_	

⊠ Email kckwan@ieee.org

Phone

(HK) +852-91887480 (DE) +49-160 99212145

> Address Konstanz, Germany

Google Scholar https://scholar.google.com/citatio ns?hl=en&user=IxV7fuwAAAAJ

> **Webpage** kckwan.github.io

Preferred Start Date 2023

Publications (Selected)

Published

- Autocomplete Repetitive Stroking with Image Guidance. Y. Chen, K.C. Kwan, L.Y. Wei, and H. Fu. In SIGGRAPH Asia 2021 Technical Communications, Tokyo, Japan, ACM, December 2021
- Multi-class Inverted Stippling (2021), C. Schulz, K.C. Kwan (joint first author), M. Becher, D. Baumgartner, G. Reina, O. Deussen, and D. Weiskopf. In ACM Transactions on Graphics (SIGGRAPH Asia 2021 issue). ACM, 40 (2021), 6. 245.
- **3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR** (2021), H. Ye, <u>K.C. Kwan</u>, and H. Fu. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization & Computer Graphics* (TVCG), IEEE, 01: 1-1.
- Automatic Image Checkpoint Selection for Guider-Follower Pedestrian Navigation (2020), K.C. Kwan, and H. Fu. In Computer Graphics Forum (CGF), Wiley, Vol. 40, No. 1, pp. 357-368.
- ARAnimator: in-situ character animation in mobile AR with user-defined motion gestures (2020), H. Ye, <u>K.C. Kwan (joint first author)</u>, W. Su, and H. Fu. In ACM Transactions on Graphics (*SIGGRAPH 2020 issue*), ACM, 39(4), 83-1.
- Mobi3DSketch: 3D Sketching in Mobile AR (2019), K.C. Kwan and H. Fu. In *Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)*. ACM, p. 176.
- Real-time Multi-view Bimanual Gesture Recognition (2018), G. Poon, K.C. Kwan, and W.-M. Pang, In *IEEE 3rd International Conference on Signal and Image Processing (ICSIP)*, IEEE, pp. 19-23.
- Packing Vertex Data into Hardware-Decompressible Textures (2017), K.C. Kwan, X. Xu, L. Wan, T.-T. Wong, and W.-M. Pang, In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG)*, IEEE, 24.5: 1705-1716.
- Pyramid of Arclength Descriptor for Generating Collage of Shapes (2016), K.C. Kwan, C. Han, L.-T. Sinn, T.-T. Wong, and C.-W. Fu. In ACM Transactions on Graphics (SIGGRAPH Asia 2016 issue), ACM, 35(6), 229.
- Locally Scale-Invariant Descriptor for 2D Whole-Shape and Partial-Shape Matching (2015), K.C. Kwan, Ph.D. Thesis, Department of Computer Science & Engineering, The Chinese University of Hong Kong.

Patent

• Three-Dimensional Sketching in Mobile Augmented Reality (2019), PWG Application PWG/PA/709/2/2019, approved to file in US.

Unpublished

 Image Abstraction for Region Based Robotic Painting. M. Gülzow, <u>K.C. Kwan</u>, and O. Deussen. In preparation for resubmission.

Other Activates

Helper: Pacific Graphics 2018

Organizers: IEEE International Workshop on Intelligent Multimedia Applications and Design for Quality

Living 2017

Reviewer: CADCG, CAG, CGASI, CGI, Chinagraph, EG, GMP, HIS, ICSPCC, ICSC, IJIET, IMAD,

ISCMA, PG, SIGCHI, SIGGRAPH (Asia), TVCJ, UIST

Funding: UGC/FDS11/E03/15 Vision-based Two-hand Gesture Recognition and Evaluation System for

Healthcare Training, 2015/16, Hong Kong, Project Leader: Dr. PANG Wai-man

Practical Grade Piano exams (Grade 8, 2007)

Theory of Music (Grade 5, 2002)

Other: Japanese Language Proficiency Test (N3, 2013)

Archery (Member of The Chinese University of Hong Kong Archery Club)

Kendo (Member of Kentokukai Kendo Club)

Awards

Postgraduate Studentship (2009-2011) | Excell

Excellent Teaching Assistantship (2010)

Shaw College, Academic Merit (2009)

Skills

C/C++, Swift, CUDA, Java, Python, MATLAB, HTML5, JavaScript, Objective-C, C#, OpenGL, OpenCV, GLSL, OpenCL, Qt, iOS App Development, ARKit

Hobby

Computing, Reading, Video game, Puzzle game, Jogging